<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on P-Hackers</title>
    <link>https://gero1999.github.io/en/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on P-Hackers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 07:58:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gero1999.github.io/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To Cause or not to Cause</title>
      <link>https://gero1999.github.io/en/blog/to_cause_or_not_to_cause/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 07:58:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gero1999.github.io/en/blog/to_cause_or_not_to_cause/</guid>
      <description>Unraveling the Enigma of Causation: Beyond Correlation &amp;ldquo;Causation&amp;rdquo; is a term frequently tossed around in scientific and everyday conversations alike. We often hear the refrain, &amp;ldquo;Correlation is not causation,&amp;rdquo; reminding us of the pitfalls of assuming a cause-and-effect relationship based exclusively on observed associations. For example, the fact that there is a positive correlation between ice cream sales and the number of crimes does not necessarily mean that the first ones produce the last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Ethics to Clinical Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://gero1999.github.io/en/blog/bra_algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 07:58:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gero1999.github.io/en/blog/bra_algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Decision-Making in Benefit-Risk Assessment (BRA) in Pharmacovigilance In relation with clinical trials, decision-making is a critical process based on the evaluation of the Benefit-Risk Assessment (BRA). BRA measure is used to make a binary operation: support or withhold a particular medical treatment. This assessment is paramount to ensure that the benefits of a treatment outweigh the associated risks, which corresponds one of the three basic Belmont principles. But how is it actually done?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science vs Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://gero1999.github.io/en/blog/science_vs_uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 07:58:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gero1999.github.io/en/blog/science_vs_uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>In Pursuit of Answers: Science&amp;rsquo;s Battle with Uncertainty In the vast realm of science, one pervasive theme continues to perplex even the brightest minds&amp;mdash;uncertainty. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re delving into the intricacies of mathematics, venturing into the enigmatic world of quantum physics, or unraveling the mysteries of life through biology, one thing remains constant: the elusive nature of certainty. Join us on a journey through the corridors of scientific thought as we explore three fascinating examples that showcase how science grapples with the enigma of uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
